Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Supplemental File, 1765-1998 (Box 50B-111)
  - Subject File, 1765-1998 (Box 50B-67)
    - Verhorst, Beate, “Dezentrierung des Subjekts: Untersuchungen zur Strukturierung des “Ich”; Begriffs in der Frühphase psychoanlytischer Theoriebildung (1892-1895),” undated
    - Viereck, George Sylvester, “Beszélgetés Sigmund Freuddal,” 1935
    - Wagner-Jauregg, Julius von, transcript of document regarding lay analysis, 1925, with cover letter by K. R. Eissler, 1957
    - Waibl, Elmer, “Gesellschaft und Kultur,” undated
    - Weiss, Edoardo, “Sigmund Freud Inscribing a Book for Benito Mussolini,” undated
    - Weizsäcker, Viktor von, Körpergeschehen und Neurose, excerpt concerning letters to Freud in 1932, 1947
    - Wenkart, Simon I., diary with shorthand notes from Freud lectures, 1917
    - Wiener Psychoanalytische Vereinigung, 1928-1938, 1958, undated
    - Wolman, Benjamin B., “Ecco Homo: The Story of Sigmund Freud's Life,” undated
    - Zeitschrift über psychoanalytische Pädagogik, 1926
    - Zweig, Arnold, calendar of correspondence with Freud, undated
    - Unidentified notes and writings, undated
  - Miscellany, 1878-1991 (Box 68-111)
    Clippings, periodicals, reprints, newsletters, bylaws, rosters, programs, invitations, pictorial printed matter, catalogs, brochures, and publication notices.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material and therein chronologically.
    - Brochures, rosters, and bylaws, 1954, 1963-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 68)
    - Clippings
      - 1900-1954, (6 folders)
      - 1955 (Box 69)
      - 1956
        - Jan.-May, (6 folders)
        - May-June, (8 folders) (Box 70)
        - July-Oct., (7 folders) (Box 71)
        - Nov.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 72)
      - 1957
        - Jan.-Mar., (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 73)
        - Apr.-Dec., (5 folders)
      - 1958-1960, (7 folders) (Box 74)
      - 1961, (7 folders) (Box 75)
      - 1962, (2 folders) (Box 76)
      - 1963, (5 folders)
      - 1964, (7 folders); (1 folder) (Box 77, Box 78)
      - 1965, (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box 79)
      - 1966, (2 folders); (7 folders) (Box 80, Box 81)
      - 1967, (5 folders); (7 folders); (3 folders) (Box 82, Box 83)
      - 1968, (4 folders); (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box 84, Box 85)
      - 1969, (6 folders); (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box 86, Box 87)
      - 1970, (2 folders); (6 folders); (8 folders); (4 folders) (Box 88, Box 89, Box 90)
      - 1971, (4 folders); (5 folders); (6 folders); (7 folders); (2 folders) (Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94)
      - 1972, (4 folders); (8 folders); (7 folders) (Box 95, Box 96)
      - 1973, (7 folders); (8 folders); (6 folders) (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99)
      - 1974, (1 folder); (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 100, Box 101)
      - 1975, (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 102)
      - 1976, (2 folders)
      - 1977, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 103)
      - 1978-1981, (9 folders)
      - 1982-1985, (8 folders) (Box 104)
      - 1986-1991, undated, (7 folders) (Box 105)
    - Commemorative art reproductions, catalogs, 1979, undated
    - Extracts from books, 1878-1982, undated
    - Miscellaneous organizational mailings and photocopied material, 1925-1928, 1951-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - Newsletters
      - 1956-1984, (6 folders)
      - 1985-1987, undated (Box 107)
    - Periodicals and reprints
      - 1907, 1937-1959, (7 folders)
      - 1960-1971, (5 folders) (Box 108)
      - 1973-1986, (5 folders) (Box 109)
      - 1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 110)
    - Pictorial printed matter including calendars, greeting card, postcards, and prints, 1946, 1960-1969, 1980, undated See also Oversize
    - Programs and invitations
      - 1914, 1937, 1947-1949, 1957-1978, (5 folders)
      - 1979-1990, undated, (4 folders) (Box 111)
    - Publication notices, 1914, 1947-1986, undated, (4 folders)
- Interviews and Recollections, 1914-1998 (Box 112-134)
  - Set A, 1914-1998 (Box 112-125)
    Interviews with Freud associates, patients, and family members conducted by K. R. Eissler and recollections about Freud contained in correspondence, writings, and notes sent to or collected by Eissler.
    Arranged as interviews and recollections and alphabetically thereunder by name of individual.
    - Interviews See also Containers 122-126, same heading and Closed (Box 112)
      - Abraham, Hilda, 1953
      - Alexander, Franz, 1953-1954
        - Copy 1
        - Copy 2
      - Altmann, S., 1956
      - Ames, Thaddeus H., 1952
      - Angel, Klaus, 1958
      - Balint, Michael, 1956
      - Barjansky, Catherine, 1956
      - Barsis, Mrs. Max, 1956
      - Bauer, Julius, 1953
      - [Bauer, Karl?], undated
      - Bender, Lauretta, 1954
      - Benedek, Therese, 1953
      - Benjamin, H., 1960 (Box 113)
      - Bennet, E. A., 1972
      - Berdach, Rahel, 1954
      - Berg, [?], sister of Alban Berg, 1953
      - Berlin, Isaiah, 1967, 1998
      - Bernays, Anna Freud, 1952
        - May
        - June
      - Bernays, Hella, 1952
      - Bibring, Edward, 1953
      - Bibring, Grete, 1954
      - Blanton, Smiley, 1952
      - Bleuler, Manfred, 1954
      - Blumgart, Leonard, 1952
      - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1959
      - Brentano, John, 1954
      - Brunswick, David, 1953
      - Casparius, Hans, 1956
      - Cassirer Bernfeld, Suzanne, undated
      - Chernakov, Sasha, 1952
      - Dehn, Adolf, 1959 (Box 114)
      - Dehn-Thomas, Mura, 1960
      - Deming, Julia, 1953
      - Deri, Frances, 1953
      - Deutsch, Felix and Helene, 1954
      - Dormandi, Mrs. Ladislas, 1957
      - Dreikurs, Rudolf, 1954
      - Eisenklam, Dorian, 1961
      - Elias, Ada, 1953
      - Emerich, Paul, 1956
      - Federn, Ernst, 1952
      - Fehl, Siegfried, 1952
      - Ferriere, Louis E., 1961
      - Fichtl, Paula, 1955-1956
      - Foges, Elsa, 1953
        - Jan. 7
        - Feb. 14
        - Apr. 25
      - Frankl, Oscar, 1953 (Box 115)
      - Frankl, Viktor, 1959
      - Frankley, Gerta, 1951
      - Freud, Anna, 1956
      - Freud, Harry, 1952
      - Freud, Oliver, 1953
      - Frink, Angelica Bijur (Mrs. Horace), 1952
      - Fürth, Otto, 1954
      - Fürth, Yulo, 1956
      - Glover, Edward, 1953
      - Graf, Herbert, 1959
      - Graf, Mrs. Herbert, 1960
      - Graf, Max, 1952
      - Grinker, Roy R., undated
      - Gross, Alfred, 1954
      - Hammerschlag, Bertha, 1951
      - Hammerschlag, Ernst, undated
      - Hawkins, Mary O'Neil, 1953
      - Heller, Judith Bernays, 1952
      - Hirst, Albert (Box 116)
        - 1951
        - 1952
      - Hitschmann, Eduard
        - 1952
        - 1953
        - 1954
      - Hofmann, Else, 1953
      - Jackson, Edith Banfield, 1954
      - Jekels, Ludwig
        - 1951
        - circa 1953
      - Jelliffe, Mrs. Smith Ely, 1954
      - Johannsen, M. W., 1953 (Box 117)
      - Jung, C. G., 1953
      - Kaiser, Hellmuth, 1958
      - Kasanjian, V., 1958
      - Kauders, Walter, 1953
      - Kelsen, Hans, 1953
      - Klein, Melanie, 1953
      - Klemper, Paul, 1952
      - Koestler, Arthur, 1953
      - Koestler, Mrs. Arthur, 1953
      - Kosawa, Heisaku, undated
      - Kris, Ernst, 1953
      - Kritz, Leo, 1962, undated
      - Kurokawa, [?], 1952
      - Lachenbruch, Mr. and Mrs., 1953
      - Lampl, Hans, 1953
      - Langstadt, Fred F., 1952
      - Laurvik, [?], 1952
      - Lederer, Hans, 1956
      - Leeuw, Charles van der, 1954
      - Leftwich, Joseph, 1956 (Box 118)
      - Liebman, Julius, 1954
      - Lippman, Hyman S., 1954
      - Maastright, Anna, 1954
      - Maeder, Alfonse, 1953
      - Meier, C. A., 1954
      - Meng, Heinrich, 1954
      - Meyer, Greta, 1973
      - Motesitzky, Henriette and Marie-Louise von, 1972
      - Murray, H. A., 1954
      - Niedinger, [?], 1953
      - Novotny, Fritz, 1954
      - Oberndorf, Clarence P., 1952
        - Sept.-Nov.
        - Dec.
      - Paneth, Marie, 1955
      - Pankejeff, Sergius (Box 119)
        - 1952
          - July 25-26
          - July 27
          - July 28-30
          - Aug. 1
        - 1954
          - July 28
          - July 30-31
          - Aug. 3-4
        - 1955
          - July 30
          - July 31 (Box 120)
          - Aug. 1-2
      - Patak, Erna, 1954
      - Paul, David, 1953
      - Penrose, L. S., 1953
      - Pfister, Oskar, 1953
      - Pollak, Max, 1952
      - Pollak, Max (1886-1970) and wife, 1953
      - Putnam, Marian C., 1958
      - Rank, Beata, 1953-1954
      - Regele, [?], 1954
      - Reich, Ann, 1956
      - Reich, Valerie, 1953
      - Reich, Wilhelm, 1952 (Box 121)
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
      - Reik, Theodor, 1954
        - Mar. 5
        - Sept. 28
      - Reiman, Rudolf, 1964
      - Ritholz, Sophie, 1956
      - Riviere, Joan, 1953
      - Róheim, Géza, 1952
      - Rosenfeld, Eva, 1953
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
      - Sachs, Emmy, 1953 (Box 122)
      - Sarasin, Philipp, 1954
      - Schacherl, Max, 1954-1956
      - Schmiedeberg, Walter, 1954
      - Schnitzler, Olga, 1953
      - Severn, Elizabeth, 1952
      - Simmell, Hertha, 1953
      - Smeltz, George W., 1959
      - Stanborough, [?], 1978
      - Stern, Adolph, 1952
      - Szabó, Szerena, 1953
      - Tansley, A. G., 1953
      - Tauber, Dana, undated
      - Thompson, Clara, 1952
      - Urbantschitsch, Rudolf von, 1953
      - Viereck, George Sylvester, 1952
      - Von Brücke, Dora, 1953
      - Von Freund, Roszi, 1953
      - Weil, Frederic, re Sergius Pankejeff, 1955 (Box 123)
      - Weinmann, Peter, 1953
      - Weiss, Edoardo
        - 1954, Apr.
        - 1954, undated
      - Wittels, Lilly, 1954
      - Wohlprecht, [?], 1954
      - Woolf, Leonard, 1956
      - Wulf, Mosheh, 1962, undated
      - Zelenka, Otto, 1954
      - Zweig, Adam, 1952
    - Recollections (Box 124)
      - Alexander, Franz, undated
      - Alexander, Jerome, 1951
      - Allport, Gordon W., 1958
      - Bárány, Ida, 1964
      - Baumgardt, David, circa 1938
      - Beckh-Widmanstetter, H. A., undated
      - Behrman, A. (Arnold Hillriegel), 1938
      - Bibring, Edward, 1952
      - Boehm, Felix, 1956
      - Brychta-Graf, Olga, 1953
      - Chatterji, Suniti Kumar, 1949
      - Chernakov, Sasha, 1952
      - De Monchy, René, 1952
      - Dehn, Adolph, undated
      - Deri, Frances, 1953
      - Deuticke, Franz, 1952
      - Deutsch, Felix, circa 1949
      - Fichtl, Paula, 1952, undated
      - Finzi, N. S., 1954
      - Foulkes, S. H., 1969
      - Freud, Martin, undated
      - Friedjung, B. E., 1966
      - Friedländer, Otto, 1954
      - Friedmann, Max W., 1954
      - Friemel, Fritz, undated
      - Frohlich-Bume, Lili, 1970
      - Fürth-Brams, Hertha, 1951
      - Gerard, R. W., 1958
      - Goetz, Bruno
        - 1952, 1967
        - Undated
      - Gross, [?], regarding “Elizabeth von R.,” 1953
      - Grotjahn, Martin, 1954
      - Hall, H. Duncan, undated
      - Hall, Robert, 1963, undated
      - Haller, Ferdinand, 1959
      - Heller, Judith Bernays, 1953
      - Hermann, Robert, 1967
      - Hitschmann, Eduard, undated
      - Hofer, Otto, 1958
      - Hollstein, Trude, 1954
      - Hölzer-Weinck, Irene, 1958
      - Hopkins, Prynce, 1954
      - Jekels, Ludwig, undated
      - Juliusburger, Otto, 1952, undated
      - Klingmüller-Paquet, Henriette, 1953
      - Knoepfmacher, Hugo, 1961, undated
      - Krafft, Margaret R., undated
      - Krausz, Wilhelm Viktor, 1952
      - Krieger, Raya Raissa, 1953
      - Kriser, Rudolf, 1954
      - Kükelhan, John, 1965
      - Kvergic-Kraus, Gertrude, 1952
      - Lacassagne, A., 1954
      - Laforgue, René, 1952
      - Levy, Erwin, 1982
      - Levy, Kata, undated
      - Lewinson, H. B., 1956
      - Lobner, Hans, 1973 (Box 125)
      - Loewy, Hanna M., 1975-1979, 1998
      - Lothar, Ernst, undated
      - Low, Barbara
        - 1954, undated
        - Undated
      - Michaels, Joseph J., 1954
      - Miscellaneous, 1914-1975, undated
      - Moebius, Emy I., 1952
      - Orgel, Samuel Zachary, undated
      - Paneth, Marie, undated
      - Pankejeff, Sergius, 1978
      - Patak, Erna, 1954
      - Peck, Abigail S., 1962
      - Peck, Martin, 1953
      - Reik, Theodor, undated
      - Reiss, Elsa, 1953
      - Riklin, Franz, undated
      - Ritholz, Sophie, 1956
      - Rosenfeld, Eva, 1977
      - Rosenfeld, Valti, 1967
      - Sachs, Oscar, 1958
      - Samet, B., 1953, undated
      - Scheu, Robert, 1954
      - Stolper, Toni, 1956
      - Tansley, A. G.
        - 1954
        - Undated
      - Teirich, Valentin, 1954
      - Thompson, Dorothy, 1953
      - Urbach-Federn, Annie, 1952
      - Urbantschitsch, Rudolf von
        - 1952
        - 1956
      - Von Mirtow, Paula Fürth, undated
      - Wagner, Richard, 1952
      - Waldinger, Ernst, 1952
      - Weiss, Edoardo, undated
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
      - Williams, E. A., 1967
      - Winterstein, Alfred, 1954
      - Wulf, Mosheh, 1948
      - Yabe, Yaekichi, 1931
      - Zilbourg, Gregory, undated
      - Zimmerman, M., 1954
      - Zweig, Margarete Beatrice, 1953
      - Unidentified, 1976
  - Set B, 1939-1974 (Box 126-134)
    Interviews with Freud associates, patients, and family members conducted by K. R. Eissler.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of individual.
    - Interviews (Box 126)
      - Augenfeld, Felix, 1954
      - Bibring, Grete, 1954
      - Bienenfeld, Rudolf, 1953
      - Binswanger, Ludwig, 1954
      - Bircher, Max, 1954
      - Birnstein, Max, 1955
      - Blum, Ernst, undated
      - Blum, Victor, 1953
      - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1954
      - Breuer, Hanna, 1954
      - Brücke, [?], 1958
      - Cassirer Bernfeld, Suzanne, 1953, 1959
      - Deutsch, Lucy Bernays, 1952
      - Eisler, Paula, 1954
      - Eissler, Margit, 1952
      - Elbogen, [?], 1953
      - Engel, Stephen, 1954
      - Ephron, [?], 1960
      - Fenichel, Hanna, 1953
      - Figdor, [Melanie?], 1956
      - Flournoy, Henri, 1953
      - Freud, Margarethe (Magnus), undated (Box 127)
      - Friedemann, M., 1954
      - Glanz, Heinrich, 1957
      - Glanz, Selma, 1957
      - Gurewich, Vladimir, 1955
      - Haas, [?], 1953
      - Häberlin, Paul, 1953
      - Harms, Ernst, 1957 (Box 128)
      - Heller, Judith Bernays, 1952
      - Hirsch, Oskar, and [?] Zinner, 1953
      - Hitschmann, Hedwig, 1953
      - Hollstein, Trude, 1954
      - Indra, Herman, 1954
      - Jackson, Edith Banfield, 1954
      - Jacobi, [?], 1953
      - Jacobson, Pauline, 1964 (Box 129)
      - Jerusalem, Mr. and Mrs., 1955
      - Jokl, Robert H., 1953
      - Keller, Adolf, 1953
      - Kluge, [?], 1954
      - Knoepfmacher, Hugo, 1952
      - Krafft, Margaret R., 1954
      - Krausz, Victor Wilhelm, 1952
      - Lambda, Peter, 1953
      - Leder, Marie, 1954
      - Leichter, Otto, regarding Otto Bauer, 1954
      - Leipen, [?], 1952
      - Liebman, Nelly, 1956
      - Loewenstein, Rudolph Maurice, 1952
      - Loewenstein, Sophie Freud, 1953 (Box 130)
        - 1952, Mar. 30 and 1952, Apr. 21
        - Apr. 24
        - May 30
      - Lustig, Robert, 1959
      - Lüthy, Emil, 1954
      - Mack, Cecile, 1953
      - Maenchen, Anja, 1953
      - Maenchen, Otto, 1953
      - Mahler-Werfel, Alma, 1953
      - Marlé, Arnold, 1953
      - Michel, Loschka, 1960
      - Moebius, Ilse, 1953
      - Mopp, Maximilian, 1953
      - Müller, Max, 1954
      - Niedermeyer, [?], 1953
      - Nunberg, Herman, 1953
      - Pankejeff, Sergius
        - 1953
          - Folder 1
          - Folder 2
        - 1957, June 25-26 (Box 131)
        - 1958
          - July 8-13
          - Aug. 3-4
          - Aug. 7
          - Aug. 8
        - 1960, July 29
      - Papanek, Ernst, 1959
      - Patzau, Natalie, 1958
      - Paul, David, 1953
      - Peck, Mrs. Martin, 1953
      - Peschke-Schmutzer, [?], 1956
      - Philipp, Oscar, and son, 1958
      - Pick, Maria, 1958
      - Pötzl, Otto, 1953
      - Powers, Lillian Delger, 1952
      - Presser, Karl, 1953 (Box 132)
      - Reiss, Leo J., 1953
      - Rie, Bella, 1953
      - Rie, Robert, 1953
      - Robitschek, Stefan, 1954
      - Roden, Max, 1955
      - Romain, [?], (Bella Rie's daughter), 1953
      - Rosenbaum, Milton, 1955
      - Sarasin, Philipp, 1954
      - Schalk, Lili, 1953
      - Scheu, Robert, 1954
      - Scholem, Fanya, 1956
      - Schönberner, Franz, 1954
      - Schulhof, Mimi, 1956
      - Schultz, I. H., 1968
      - Schur, Max, 1953
      - Schwarz, [?], 1953
      - Seyler, Clarence A., 1953
      - Silbermann, Maximilian, 1956
      - Spitz, René A., 1953
      - Steinberg, Isaac, 1956
      - Steiner, Berta, 1955 (Box 133)
      - Stenby, [?], undated
      - Sterba, Richard, 1955
      - Stiedry, [?], 1958
      - Stolper, Toni, 1956
      - Straus, Mrs. Nathan, 1957
      - Swoboda, Hermann, 1953, 1956, 1960
      - Tamm, A., 1954
      - Telatko, [?], 1955
      - Teleki, Ludwig, 1956
      - Tischler, M., 1953
      - Urbach-Federn, Annie, 1952, 1974
      - Versteeg, [?], 1954
      - Von Leth, [?], 1954
      - Von Mises, Hilda, 1953
      - Wagner, Richard, 1953
      - Walder, Robert, 1953
      - Waldinger, Ernst, 1953
      - Wechsler, Israel Spanier, 1952
      - Wenkart, Simon I., 1958
      - Wernay, Lucy, 1953 (Box 134)
      - Zinner, [?] See Container 128, Hirsch, Oskar
      - Zweig, Arnold, 1952
    - Recollections
      - Briehl, Marie H., 1956
      - Jekels, Ludwig, 1961
      - Meng, Heinrich, undated
      - Regele, Klara, 1953
      - Rosenfeld, Eva, undated
      - Simon, Ernst, regarding Wilhelm Fliess, 1971
      - Teirich, Valentin, 1956
      - Walder, Robert, 1939
- Additions, 1912-1977 (Box 135-138)
  Correspondence, exhibit material, photographs, a case history, a recollection, an index, lists, and printed matter.
  Arranged chronologically by date of addition and thereunder by groupings that correspond to other series in the collection.
  - 2010 addition
    - General correspondence (Box 135)
      - Zweig, Arnold See also Container 44, same heading
        - From Freud, 1927-1937
        - To Freud
          - Letters, 1927-1939, (3 folders)
          - Writings filed with correspondence, circa 1939
    - Supplemental file (Box 136)
      - Centenary of Freud's birth, exhibit material, circa 1956
        - Photographs
          - Captions and credits, (3 folders)
          - Lists and notes
          - Prints
            - Bernays and Freud families See Oversize
            - People identified and unidentified See Oversize
            - Portraits of Freud
              - Paintings, drawings, cartoons, busts, statues, and medals See Oversize
              - Photographs See Oversize
            - Residences and other places associated with Freud See Oversize
            - Writings and documents by or about Freud See Oversize
        - Wall text and captions See also Oversize
          - Career and training, (5 folders)
          - Honors and tributes (Box 137)
          - Writings, (2 folders)
      - Klumpner, George H., index to the works of Freud, 1970
      - Nunberg, Herman and Margarete
        - English translations and transcripts of Freud correspondence
          - Andreas-Salomé, Lou, 1912
          - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess
            - English translations, 1926-1932
            - Transcripts, probably made by Bonaparte, 1926-1933
          - Freud to the Nunbergs, 1919, 1939, undated
          - Laforgue, René, 1923-1937
          - Unidentified Freud letters, 1919, 1937-1938
        - Photographs, 1939, 1948, 1970s
        - Printed matter, 1962-1977, undated
        - “Rat man” case history, undated
        - Recollections by Margarete Nunberg, fragment, undated
  - 2019 addition (Box 138)
    - General correspondence
      - Federn, Paul, 1913
      - Hartmann, Heinz, originals, 1927-1939
- Artifacts and Painting, circa 6th century BCE-1936 CE (Box VA 1-VA 3)
  Pocket watch, a small Greek statue, and an oil portrait painting of Freud.
  - Pocket watch, undated (Box VA 1)
  - Small Greek statue, circa 6th century - 1st century BCE (Box VA 2)
  - Oil portrait painting of Freud, 1936 (Box VA 3)
- Closed, 1952-1956 (Box X 1-X 2)
  Interviews.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Interviews and Recollections (Box X 1)
    - Interviews (Container 112-119)
      - Freud, Ernestine Drucker, 1953 Closed until 2053, (3 folders)
      - Heller, Judith Bernays, 1953 Closed until 2057, (3 folders)
      - Weiss, Edoardo, 1952 Closed until 2057 (Box X 2)
      - Identity withheld
        - Interviewee A, 1956 Closed until 2038
        - Interviewee B, 1953 Closed until 2057
- Oversize, 1859-1985 (Box OV 1-OV 20)
  Writings, university and military records, legal documents, correspondence, patient case files, notes, exhibit material, newspaper clippings, family tree, sketch, photograph, and map and chart.
  - Family Papers (Box OV 1)
    - Subject File
      - Freud, Amalia and Jacob
        - Miscellaneous legal documents, including Freud family birth and death data, 1859 (Container 13)
      - Freud, Josef, documents regarding conviction for counterfeiting rubles, 1865-1866 (Container 14)
  - General Correspondence
    - Fliess, Wilhelm, 1896-1897 (Container 26)
    - Jung, C. G.
      - From Freud
        - Originals, 1907 (Container 32)
  - Subject File
    - Allgemeines Krankenhaus, Vienna, Austria, patient case files
      - Originals
        - Set A, 1881-1883 (Container 45)
        - Set B, 1881-1883 (Container 45)
    - Military records
      - Originals, 1886-1887 (Container 49)
      - Photocopies, 1885-1888 (Container 49)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings
      - Photocopies and originals, 1932 (Container 49)
    - Patients
      - Notes, undated (Container 50A)
    - University records
      - Applications
        - As student, 1873 (Container 50A)
      - Certificate of classes taken, 1879 (Container 50A)
  - Writings* (Container 50A) (Box OV 2, Reel 1)
    Microfilm shelf no. 21,186
    *Titles are cited as they appear on the manuscripts, with brackets denoting either a differing published title from that on the manuscript or a descriptive summary of material which remained untitled and/or unpublished. Dates bracketed after a title indicate the probable year a manuscript was written.
    - 1877
      - “Beobachtungen über Gestaltung und feineren Bau der als Hoden beschriebenen Lappenorgane des Aals” [b]**, photocopy of printed publication, **Bracketed letters in lower case after an entry refer to the code used by James Strachey in Indexes and Bibliographies, volume 24 of The Standard Edition of the Complete Psychological Works of Sigmund Freud (London: Hogarth Press and Institute of Psycho-analysis, 1974) and, for works published after 1974, by Ingeborg Meyer-Palmedo and Gerhard Fichtner, Freud-Bibliographie mit Werkkonkordanz (Frankfurt am Main: S. Fischer Verlag, 1989). The letter designations were established in these bibliographic guides for ordering purposes and do not necessarily reflect the sequence in which the manuscripts were written or published within a given year.
    - circa 1882
      - “Verzeichnis der Briefe und Liebeszeichen die Ich von meiner theuren Martha erhalten habe,” holograph manuscript
    - 1883-1886
      - “Unsere Geheim-Chronik begonnen am 25 Jan. 83,” holograph chronicle with alternating entries by Sigmund Freud and Martha Bernays on various dates in 1883, 1884, and 1886
    - 1884
      - “Die Struktur der Elemente des Nervensystems” [1882] [f], photocopy of printed publication
    - 1885
      - “Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Cocawirkung” [a], offprint inscribed by Freud to Josef Breuer
      - “Ein Fall von Muskelatrophie mit ausgebreiteten Sensibilitätsstörungen (Syringomyelie)” [c], offprint inscribed by Freud to Josef Breuer
    - 1886